Guide to the John S. Chipman Papers, 1948-2014 and undated RL.11495
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
John S. Chipman papers
1948-2014 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Chipman, John Somerset, 1926-
RL.11495
15.5 Linear Feet 11 boxes
Collection consists of writings, research, correspondence, and professional files collected or created by John Chipman over the course of his career as an economist and professor at the University of Minnesota. Areas of research include welfare economics, international trade, econometrics, and translations of the writings of Pareto.
Arrangement
Arranged into series: Name Files, Writings, and Engagements.
Biographical / Historical
John Somerset Chipman (1926- ) was born in Montreal, Canada. He received his Ph.D. from Johns Hopkins University in 1951, and taught at the University of Minnesota from 1955 until his retirement as Regents' Professor in 2007. He was elected to the National Academy of Sciences in 1993. His most recent publications include The Theory of International Trade, 2 vols., Cheltenham, U.K.: Edward Elgar, 2008-9; "Multiple Equilibrium under CES Preferences", Economic Theory, 45 (2010); "Gauss-Markov Theorem", International Encyclopedia of Statistical Sciences, Berlin: Springer, 2010; Advanced Econometric Theory (London and New York: Routledge, 2011); and "Detrimental Externalities, Pollution Rights, and the Coase Theorem" (with Guoqiang Tian), Economic Theory, 49 (2012).
*biography copied from Chipman's University of Minnesota faculty website, 2017.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The John S. Chipman Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2016.
Collection Overview
Chipman's papers consist of drafts, publications, lecture notes, correspondence, and other files documenting his scholarship, writings, and teachings at the University of Minnesota. Prominent themes include international trade, with extensive research on West Germany during the Cold War; linear programming; welfare economics; econometrics; the writings and impact of Vilfredo Pareto; and Chipman's collaboration and friendships with other economists.
The range of Chipman's research and writings are represented in the Writings Series, where files are arranged alphabetically by title. Files typically include drafts and published versions, usually offprints, as well as occasional correspondence and notes by Chipman documenting the development of the paper or essay.
The Name Files series includes a range of material (including correspondence, writings, notes, and subject files), arranged alphabetically by name, that document his professional relationships and communications with publishers, professional organizations, or other scholars, as well as his ongoing collaboration with other economists, including Leonid Hurwicz, James C. Moore, Tjalling Koopmans, Paul Samuelson, Eugen Slutsky, and Ragnar Frisch.
Finally, the Engagements series includes Chipman's lecture notes, exams, and reading lists from his years as a professor in the Economics Department, as well as event files from conferences, workshops, travels, awards, and other activities over the course of his career as an economist.
Economics -- Study and teaching -- United States; Welfare economics -- Research; International trade -- Economic aspects; Econometrics; Germany -- Economics -- 20th century; Hurwicz, Leonid; Moore, James C., 1936-; Pareto, Vilfredo, 1848-1923; University of Minnesota. Dept. of Economics -- Faculty; Slutsky, Evgeny Evgenievich, 1880-1948; Frisch, Ragnar, 1895-1973; Samuelson, Paul A. (Paul Anthony), 1915-2009
- Name Files, 1948-2014; 1
  - Alt, Franz, 1997-2001 (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents
    includes memoirs
  - American Economic Review, 1979-1980 (Box 1)
    includes information about exact consumer's surplus
  - Aldine Publishing Company, 1964-1966 (Box 1)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1979-2002 (Box 1)
  - American Economic Association, 1954 (Box 1)
  - Anderson, Jim, 1988-1990 (Box 1)
  - Anderson, Ted, 1998-2005 (Box 1)
  - Balasko, Yves, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Barbera, Salvador, 1988-1989 (Box 1)
  - Beckmann, Martin, 1953 (Box 1)
  - Bhagwati, Jagdish, 1966-2003 (Box 1)
  - Bjerkholt, Olav, 1994-2013; 2 folders (Box 1)
    includes information about Frisch's collected papers
  - Blitz, Rudolph, 1965-1967 (Box 1)
  - Bousquet, Georges-Henri, 1974-1976 (Box 1)
  - Boyer, Russell S., 2007 (Box 1)
  - Braguinsky, Serguey, 1998 (Box 1)
  - Brazil, 1964-1965 (Box 1)
    includes information about his experiences in Brazil
  - Canadian Economic Association, 1966-1972; 2 folders (Box 1)
    includes information about his Pareto commemoration; includes discussion of creating a new journal
  - Chipman, John, 1963-2014 and undated (Box 1)
    Curriculum vitae; photograph of Chipman and Samuelson; newspaper clipping with biography of Chipman; journal clippings
  - Chipman, John, and Tadashi Inoue, 2001-2002 (Box 1)
  - Chipman, John, and Jean-Sebastian Lenfant, 1999-2013; 3 folders (Box 1)
    includes information about revisions of a Slutsky article; includes information about physiocratic tax theory; includes information about political economy history
  - Chipman, John, and James C. Moore, 1979 (Box 1)
    includes information about an Econometrica paper "Compensating Variation as a Measure of Welfare Change"
  - Chipman, John, and Peter Winker, 1994-2006; 3 folders (Box 1)
    includes research and drafts
  - Chow, Gregory, 2003 (Box 1)
  - Christ, Carl, 13 July (Box 1)
  - Consumers for World Trade, 1985 (Box 1)
    includes panel remarks
  - Cooper, W. W., and A. Charnes, 1954-1964 (Box 1)
  - Corden, W. M., 1969-1972 (Box 1)
  - Chipman, John, and John Creedy, and Denis O'Brien, 1966-1984 (Box 1)
  - Dalloz Encyclopedia, 2001-2002 (Box 1)
    includes correspondence about an article in the Dalloz Encyclopedia
  - Dano, S., 1955 (Box 1)
  - Davis, Julia, 1991-1993 (Box 1)
    includes photos
  - Debreu, Gerard, 1958 (Box 1)
  - Dhrymes, P. J., 1970-1977 (Box 1)
  - Duke, 1959 (Box 1)
    includes correspondence with Duke staff
  - Durbin, James, and Geoffrey Watson, 1965 (Box 1)
  - Economic Commission for Latin America, 1961-1963 (Box 1)
    includes information about ECLA
  - Econometrica, 1957-1958; 2 folders (Box 1)
    includes information about Lionel McKenzie's manuscript "Competitive Equilibrium and the Pareto Optimum"
  - Elgar, Edward, 1990-1991 (Box 1)
  - Elliott, G. A., 1948-1949 (Box 1)
  - Eltis, Walter, 2000 (Box 1)
  - European Journal of the History of Economic Thought, 2004-2005 (Box 1)
  - Fabella, Raul V., and Jose Encarnacion Jr., and Emmanuel S. De Dios, 1992-1996 (Box 1)
    includes information for the Festschrift for Jose Encarnacion
  - Faber, Malte, 1972-1997; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Feiwel, George R., 1985-1989 (Box 1)
    includes information about Joan Robinson
  - Fishburn, Peter C., 1970-1971 (Box 1)
  - Fisher, Franklin, 1969 (Box 11)
  - University of Georgia, 1976 (Box 1)
  - Giersch, Herbert, 1978-1979 (Box 1)
  - Goldberger, 1964-1965 (Box 1)
    includes information about his book, Econometric Theory
  - Goodwin, R. M., 1950 (Box 1)
  - Gossling, W. F., 1992 (Box 1)
  - Haberler, Gottfried, 1953-1994; 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Hagemann, Harald, 2003 (Box 1)
  - Harcourt Brace Jovanovich, 1965-1988 (Box 1)
  - Hattaway, Jerry, 1972 (Box 11)
  - Hopkins Press, 1951-1987 (Box 1)
  - Humphrey, Thomas M., 1987 (Box 1)
  - Hurwicz, Leonid, 1952-1996; 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Hurwicz, Leonid, 1995-1997 (Box 11)
    Includes Hurwicz's 1997 paper draft: Feasible balanced outcome functions yielding constrained Walrasian and Lindahl allocations at Nash equilibrium points in economies with two agents with the designer knows the feasible set
  - Iowa State University, 1990-1991 (Box 1)
  - Irwin, Douglas, 1988-1994; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Jaffe, William, 1969-1977 (Box 1)
  - Johns Hopkins, 1949-1952; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Johnson, Harry, 1955 (Box 1)
    includes information on multi-sectoral multiplier theory
  - Jones, Ronald W., 1964-1992; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Jones, Ronald W., 2007 (Box 11)
  - Journal of American Statistical Association, 1952-1958 (Box 2)
  - Journal of Economic Theory, 1969-1990; 2 folders (Box 2)
    includes information about the Vanek-Bertrand paper
  - Jungenfelt, Karl G., 1981-1983 (Box 2)
  - Kalecki, Michal, 1976 (Box 2)
  - Kalman, Peter, 1974 (Box 2)
  - Kemp, Murray C., 1959-1998; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Kindleberger, Charles P., 1970-1986; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Klein, L. R., 1955-1957 (Box 2)
  - Koch, Karl-Josef, and Klaus Jaeger, 1986-1995 (Box 2)
  - Konstanz Universitat, 1971-1980; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Koopmans, Tjalling C., 1950-1990; 2 folders (Box 2)
    includes information about the Cowles Commission
  - Kuhn, Harold W., 1963-1968 (Box 2)
  - La Jolla, 1964 (Box 2)
  - Langham, Max R., undated (Box 11)
    notes
  - Leamer, Edward, 1982 (Box 2)
  - Leijonhufvud, Axel, 1974 (Box 2)
  - Leijonhufvud, Axel, 1999 (Box 11)
  - Leontief, Wassily, 2005-2006 (Box 2)
  - Lerner, Abba P., 1952 (Box 2)
  - Liu, Ta-Chung, 1958-1969 (Box 2)
  - Lombardini, Siro, 1992-1994 (Box 2)
  - Luce, R. Duncan, 1965-1971 (Box 2)
  - Machlup, Fritz, 1976-1978 (Box 2)
    includes correspondence from other people regarding Machlup
  - The MacMillan Company, 1966 (Box 2)
  - The Macmillan Press, 1991 (Box 2)
  - Manglin, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Marschak, Jacob, 1956-1999; 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Marsh, Donald B., 1948-1952 (Box 2)
  - Martina, Alan, 1983-1984 (Box 2)
  - McFadden, Dan, 1962-1972; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - McGraw-Hill, Inc., 1961-1994 (Box 2)
  - McKenzie, Lionel W., 1955-1990; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - McKinnon, Ronald I., 1959-2007; 3 folders (Box 2)
  - McNally, Rand, 1965-1967 (Box 2)
  - Metzler, Lloyd, 1949 (Box 2)
  - Meyer, John, 1956 (Box 2)
  - Midutani, 1954 (Box 2)
  - (Royal) Military College, 1950-1952 (Box 2)
  - Monissen, Hans, 1989-2007 (Box 2)
  - Moore, James C., 1964-2003 (Box 2)
  - Mundell, Robert, 1978-1997; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Neary, Peter, 1997-1998 (Box 2)
  - (University of) New Mexico, 1957-1958 (Box 2)
  - New Palgrave Dictionary, 1983-1986 (Box 2)
  - Neudecker, Heinz, 1994-1995 (Box 2)
  - Newman, Peter, 1965-1968 (Box 2)
  - North-Holland Publishing Company, 1972-1990; 4 folders (Box 2)
    includes correspondence with Michielsen, van Koten, & Hamelynck as representatives of the company
  - New York Times, 1953 (Box 2)
  - Prescott, Ed, 1985 (Box 2)
  - Quarterly Journal of Economics, 1955-1967; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Quarterly Journal of Economics, 1966-1968; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Raiffa, Howard, 1953 (Box 3)
  - Rao, C. R., 1969-1979 (Box 3)
  - Rao, M. M., 1957-1999; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Rauscher, Guido, 2003-2007; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Rayner, Arthur, 1967-2007 (Box 3)
  - Readings in Econometrics, 1967-1970 (Box 3)
  - Regents' Professorship, 1978-1981 (Box 3)
  - Review of Econ. & Statistics, 1952-1956 (Box 3)
  - Richardson, J. David, 1977 (Box 3)
    includes comments on each other's papers (i.e. Richardson & Brito's Germany paper)
  - Richter, Rudolf, 1980-1981 (Box 3)
  - Ringwald, Karl, 1981-1985 (Box 3)
  - Robinson, Sherman, 2007 (Box 3)
  - Rochester, 1960-1983; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Ronning, Gerd, 1982-1987 (Box 3)
  - Row, Peterson & Co. & John Wiley & Sons, Inc., 1953-1964 (Box 3)
  - Samuelson, Paul A., 1964-2010; 14 folders (Box 3)
    includes suggestions and comments on each other's papers (i.e. "One Way to Measure")
  - Savage, L. J., 1956 (Box 3)
  - Scheer, Christian, 2000-2003 (Box 3)
  - Science, 1990-1995 (Box 3)
  - Sen, Amartya, 1973-1986 (Box 3)
  - Sir George Williams University, 1963 (Box 3)
  - Sheynin, Oscar, 1993-2001 (Box 3)
  - Studies in International Economics, 1975-1976 (Box 3)
  - Sims, Chris, 1967-1986; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Slutsky, Eugen, 2005; 3 folders (Box 3)
    includes correspondence with Frisch, Bortkiewicz
  - Slutsky, Eugen, 1998-2005; 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Sohmen, Egon, 1963-1965 (Box 4)
  - Sohmen, Regine, 1973-1981 (Box 4)
  - Solow, Robert, 1951-1988 (Box 4)
  - Somers, Harold M., 1951 (Box 4)
  - Sondermann, Dieter, 1980-1985 (Box 4)
  - Sonnenschein, Hugo, 1964-1974; 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Srinivasan, T. N., 1987 (Box 4)
  - Stiftung Volkswagenwerk, 1981-1987 (Box 4)
  - Stigler, Stephen, 2008-2010 (Box 4)
  - Stiglitz, Joseph E., 1969 (Box 4)
  - Supper, Meinhard, 1989-1990 (Box 4)
  - Takayama, Akira, 1990-1991 (Box 4)
  - Telser, Lester, 1968-1976 (Box 4)
  - University of Tennessee, 1986-1988 (Box 4)
  - Tian, Guoqiang, 1987-2009 (Box 4)
  - Tinbergen, Jan, 1953 (Box 4)
  - University of Toronto, 1966-1968 (Box 4)
  - Tower, Edward, 1981-1992 (Box 4)
  - UNESCO, 1961-1964 (Box 4)
  - University of New Mexico, 1957 (Box 4)
  - Uzawa, Hirofumi, 1968-1988; 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Vanderbilt, 1959 (Box 4)
  - Vanek, Jaroslav, 1978 (Box 4)
  - von Humboldt, Alexander & Wolfgang Holl, 1986 (Box 4)
  - Vosgerau, Hans-Jurgen, 1984-2001 (Box 4)
  - Waelbroeck, Jean, 1960-1966 (Box 4)
  - Waters, Lindsay, 1986-1990 (Box 4)
  - Weldon, 1987-1990 (Box 4)
    includes correspondence with A. Asimakopulos about the Weldon volume
  - Westdeutscher Verlag, 1967 (Box 4)
  - Whalby, John, 1978-1980 (Box 4)
  - Wheatsheaf Books, 1984-1991 (Box 4)
  - Wiley, John and Sons (Box 4)
  - Winker, Peter, 1995-1997 (Box 4)
  - University of Wisconsin, 1968-1969 (Box 4)
    includes correspondence with Somers
  - Wold, Herman, 1953-1978; 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Wolfe, 1956 (Box 4)
  - Worgotter, Andreas, 1990-1995 (Box 4)
  - World Publishing Company, 1968 (Box 4)
  - World Scientific, 2007-2013 (Box 4)
  - Young, Warren, 1999-2007; 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Zellner, Arnold, 1967-1969 (Box 4)
  - Misc. Correspondence, 1966-2013; 2 folders (Box 4)
    includes correspondence with Yale University, University of Minnesota, University of Durham, Harvard University, etc.
- Writings, 1950-2011; 2
  - Articles, papers, and essays, 1
    - Acceptable indicators of welfare change, consumer's surplus analysis, and the Gorman Polar Form, 1981; 2 folders (Box 5)
      Drafts, offprint
    - Anderson and Rubin's limited-information maximum-likelihood method revisited, 1998 (Box 5)
      Draft
    - An application of integrability and duality theory to the classifcal transfer problem in international trade, 1998-1999 and undated; 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Aggregate demand, real national income, and the compensation principle, 1973 (Box 5)
      Reprints
    - The aggregation problem in econometrics, 1975 (Box 5)
      Reprint
    - Assembling a data base linking foreign and domestic sectors, 1995 (Box 5)
    - Balance-of-payments theory from Locke to Ricardo, 1983 and undated; 2 folders (Box 5)
      Correspondence, drafts
    - The balance of trade from mercantilist times to the present, undated (Box 5)
    - Best approximate aggregation in a multivariate model with distributed lags interpolated by spline functions, 1981 (Box 5)
    - Bibliography on mercantilism, 1993 (Box 5)
    - Bibliography on utility theory, 1995 (Box 5)
    - Bickerdike's Theory of Incipient and Optimal Tariffs, 1993 (Box 5)
      Draft, offprint
    - Calculation of objective functions for spline-lagged regressions, 1996 (Box 5)
    - Capital movement as a substitute for technology transfer: a comment, 1981 (Box 5)
      Offprint
    - The classical transfer problem and the theory of foreign exchanges, 1986; 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Closed-form solutions of general intertemporal consumption-maximization models, undated (Box 5)
    - Compensating variation as a measure of welfare change, 1976 (Box 5)
    - Compensating variation, consumers' surplus, and welfare, 1980 (Box 5)
    - The compensation principle, undated (Box 5)
    - Computational problems in linear programming, 1953 (Box 5)
    - The concepts of utility and welfare: historical and technical aspects, 2003 (Box 5)
    - Consumers' surplus as a measure of aggregate welfare, 1980 (Box 5)
    - Consumers' surplus and the compensating variation, 1979 (Box 5)
    - Continuity and uniqueness in revealed preference, 1976 (Box 5)
    - Contributions of Ragnar Frisch to economics and econometrics, 1997 (Box 5)
    - Contributions of the older German schools to the development of utility theory, 1999 (Box 5)
    - Definitions of noncentral gamma densities, 2008 (Box 5)
    - Detrimental externalities, pollution rights, and the "Coase Theorem", 2011 (Box 5)
    - Domestic adjustment to international economic disturbances: an econometric study of recent West German experience, 1983-1986; 3 folders (Box 5)
      Draft; includes proposal to Volkswagenwerk re: followup project
    - Dynamic adjustment of internal prices to external price changes, 1981-1983; 3 folders (Box 5)
      Drafts, reprint, correspondence
    - Economics Translation series (edited by Chipman), 1950s-2000s; 4 folders (Box 5)
      Includes essays 1-10 as well as correspondence, drafts
    - Efficiency of least-squares estimation of linear trend when residuals are autocorrelated, 1977-1979; 2 folders (Box 5)
      Reprint, correspondence
    - Efficiency of the sample mean when residuals follow a first order stationary markoff process, 1966-1969 (Box 5)
      Reprints, draft
    - An empirical implication of Auspitz-Lieben-Edgeworth-Pareto complementarity, 1977 (Box 5)
    - The end of the new welfare economics, 1973 (Box 5)
    - An episode in the early development of ordinal utility theory: Pareto's letters to Hermann Laurent 1899-1902, 1976 (Box 5)
    - Equilibrium in a competitive economy, 1975 (Box 5)
    - Estimating price responses of West German imports and exports, 1992 (Box 5)
      Drafts, reprint
    - Estimation of distributed lags by spline functions, 2000 (Box 5)
    - Estimation of net-import demand functions for the Federal Republic of Germany 1959-1982, 1985 (Box 5)
      Drafts
    - Estimation of an intertemporal offer function, undated (Box 5)
      Draft proposal to the National Science Foundation
    - Exchange-rate flexibility and resource allocation, 1980 (Box 5)
    - Exchange-rate theory in light of recent experience, 1990 (Box 5)
    - Explaining changing patterns of West German international trade: Economic and institutional factors, 1987 (Box 5)
    - Extension of a theorem of Hausdorff, 1963 (Box 5)
    - External economies of scale and competitive equilibrium, 1967-1970; 3 folders (Box 5)
      Reprint, drafts, correspondence
    - Factor price equalization and the Stolper-Samuelson Theorem, 1969 (Box 6)
    - The foundations of utility, 1960 (Box 6)
    - A fundamental property of systems characterized by nonnegative-matrices, 1950s (Box 6)
      Correspondence, reader comments, draft
    - Fundamental theorems of welfare economics, 1974-2007 (Box 6)
    - Further notes on optimal tariffs, undated (Box 6)
    - General equlibrium and welfare in international trade, 2009 (Box 6)
    - A general-equilibrium econometric model of an open economy, 1988 (Box 6)
    - A general-equilibrium framework for analyzing the responses of imports and exports, 1981 (Box 6)
      Drafts, reprints
    - A general-equilibrium intertemporal model of an open economy, 1992 (Box 6)
    - A generalized matrix cauchy inequality and its application to biased estimation, 1994 (Box 6)
    - Generalized maximum-likelihood estimation of the linear expenditure system with lognormal distribution, 1990 (Box 6)
    - Globalization, technology, and income distribution, 1998 (Box 6)
    - Haavelmo's contributions to simultaneous-equations estimation, 2012 (Box 6)
    - Haberler on competitive advantage and international competitiveness, 1990 (Box 6)
    - Hick's interpretation of Keynes's general theory, 2001 (Box 6)
    - Hicksian welfare economics, 1993-1994 (Box 6)
      Draft, report
    - The history of utility theory, 1999 (Box 6)
    - Homothetic preferences and aggregation, 1974 (Box 6)
    - Income curve and Professor Edgeworth's observations, undated (Box 11)
      Drafts; alternate title: The Curve of Distribution of Wealth
    - Induced technical change and patterns of international trade, 1968 (Box 6)
      Drafts, correspondence
    - The integers and the principle of mathematical induction, undated (Box 6)
    - Internal-external price relationships in the West German economy 1958-1979, 1981 (Box 6)
      Draft, reprint
    - International trade, 1987 (Box 6)
      Report
    - International trade with capital mobility: a substitution theorem, undated (Box 6)
    - Interpolation of economic time series, with application to German and Swedish data, 1991 (Box 6)
      Draft, chapter photocopy
    - An interpretation of Lipsey's model of custom unions, 1996 (Box 6)
    - Intertemporal comparative advantage, 2001-2002 (Box 6)
    - Intra-industry trade, factor proportions, and aggregations, 1986, undated; 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Intra-industry trade in the Heckscher-Ohlin-Lerner-Samuelson model, 1988, 1991; 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Intra-industry trade in a loglinear model, 2000 (Box 6)
    - Introduction to international trade payments, 1995 (Box 6)
    - Introduction to multivariate analysis in econometrics, 1988 (Box 6)
    - Introductory notes on neo-classical models of economic growth, 1967 (Box 6)
      Manuscript draft
    - Irving Fisher's contributions to economic statistics and econometrics, undated (Box 6)
    - James-Stein estimation for multivariate multiple regression, undated (Box 6)
    - Lectures on the mathematical foundations of international trade theory ("Vienna Lectures"), 1970 (Box 6)
      Manuscript drafts
    - The lexographic representation of preference orderings, 1965 (Box 6)
    - Linear programming, 1952-1953, 1968 (Box 6)
      Correspondence, draft, photocopy
    - Linear restrictions, rank reduction, and biased estimation in linear regression, 1999 (Box 6)
    - The logical foundations of consumption theory, undated (Box 6)
    - Marshall's consumer's surplus in modern perspective, undated (Box 6)
    - Marshallian offer curves, 2003 (Box 6)
    - Maximum-likelihood estimation of the linear expenditure system with exponential distribution, 1991 (Box 6)
      Draft, correspondence
    - The measurement of aggregate welfare, 1991 (Box 6)
    - Measurement of inequality, 2004 (Box 6)
    - The Metzler Paradox and the transfer problem, 1985; 2 folders (Box 6)
    - A microeconometric model of the Federal Republic of Germany in its relation to the world economy, undated (Box 6)
    - Mill's "superstructure": how well does it stand up?, 1979 (Box 6)
    - The multi-sector multiplier, 1950 (Box 6)
    - Multiple equilibrium under CES preferences, 2008 (Box 6)
    - A multivariate mean-square-error test of aggregation bias for two-state aggregation procedures, 1982 and undated (Box 6)
    - The nature and meaning of equilibrium in economic theory, 1965 (Box 6)
    - A new method of estimating the effects of external on internal prices: West Germany 1958-1979, 1981; 2 folders (Box 6)
    - The new welfare economics 1939-1974, 1978 (Box 6)
    - Non-Archimedean behavior under risk: an elementary analysis, 1978 (Box 6)
    - Non-concavifiable preferences and social utility (social welfare), 2006 (Box 6)
    - A note on stability, workability, and duality in linear economic models, 1954 (Box 6)
      Correspondence and draft
    - Notes on intertemporal comparative advantage, 2000 (Box 6)
    - Notes on spline interpolation, 2001 (Box 6)